the next big thing starts looking out
like a toy meme coins Express a
sentiment in the market that is the
result of several years of good and bad
things that have happened in the
industry it's expressing the frustration
with all of the you know vaporware and
the rug pools and unfairness in the
market um it's expressing frustration
with the regulatory uncertainty and it's
kind of like giving the ultimate middle
finger to the world where it's like you
did this to us and the story is just as
important is what actually exists today
memes are just stories there's stories
and Collective beliefs and Collective
experiences that we all rally behind to
orient ourselves and to view the world
through a certain lens most people
struggle with seeing your friends making
a lot of money with one meme coin and
you're still here investing in like
those staple assets you know you're up
20% but that person's up 2,000% Charlie
Munger says if you're going to pick any
of the deadly sins don't pick Envy
there's so many better sins than Envy
you're not going to make it in a single
cycle if you can erase one crypto
narrative right now because it's garbage
which one would it be everything of
value is a meme but not all memes have
value I think that's the difference um
explain
[Music]
that game stacking crypto like it's her
to fame if you want success then take a
look
away hi Armani hey Bonnie how's it going
I'm super excited to talk to you today
because you have achieved some crazy
stuff at a very young age um for people
for people that might not be familiar
with you who is Armani Oh great question
um who's Armani uh I am I know what's
what's the what's the canonical answer
to this I'm a I'm I'm a programmer I'm a
I'm a dad I'm a I'm a I'm a human um uh
who am I um okay so I mean starting from
the beginning I mean I'm just I'm just a
programmer came into crypto I guess in
in in in
2017 uh got nerd sniped by ethereum in
the world computer and I've worked on a
bunch of stuff ever since so I mean I
really salana I think is probably where
a lot of the most notable work started
so I really came in in the early days
really before much else on the network
was built worked on a lot of the early
defi uh protocols a lot of the early
wallet infrastructure a lot of developer
tooling
and really I think played a small uh but
important part of of that kind of
initial kind of uh uh a journey uh I
suppose and fast forwarding to today uh
building a business so we've got three
parts of the business uh we've got
backpack the wallet it's a self-
custodial wallet client side key
management system connect to any app on
any chain uh like Phantom or metamask
and we have a beautiful spot and
derivatives exchange and an
amazing nft uh community of crazy people
all around the world uh that are known
as The Mad Lads I
suppose um we are going to talk about
all the things you built later but
before that you were an engineer at
Apple right that's right is that correct
because I I read yeah that was my first
job out of school yeah and a lot of
people that as the ultimate dream job
but you left that job it's high paying
it's probably very stable and then
decided hey I want to be in crypto and I
will want to build something in crypto
what was the mindset change and what
made you want to do that I I think it
was really a couple things I think the
first thing was really just becoming so
inspired after reading the ethereum
white paper it was like the coolest
technology I'd ever come across the
concept of a world computer was just so
just uh just inspiring really uh and
that was the thing that nerd sniped me
and and and and that alongside you know
that 2017 bull cycle really uh where
there was literally folks in the office
trading Bitcoin and in Discord groups
and uh uh and it just it was just like
the coolest thing ever and and I just I
just wanted to work on it was that was
it um and I think part of
what was so motivating was just how
Stark of a contrast it was relative to
to Apple in particular but just big Tech
more broadly
where apple is this huge company hugely
inspiring company for sure but it was so
secretive um I I remember I was working
on the iPhone 10 and in order to work on
the phone this is like the first iPhone
10 that ever came out was like a big
kind of device release and you had to
like go take a class to get security
clearance so that you had the right to
actually learn about what the device was
and then So eventually you go through
all this like you know security stuff
and you get the device so that you can
like start working on it on the app and
then they give you like a black cloth so
you're working on the phone in the
office but nobody else in the office can
actually see the phone and so it was
this environment where nobody really
trusts anyone at least you know when it
comes to like those like really
important new releases and you you
couldn't blog you couldn't tweet you
can't share your work publicly and uh
the whole crypto movement at the time
was really the exact opposite it was all
about open source it was all about you
know uh all these kind of crazy people
crazy young people just sharing their
ideas about kind of all the cool stuff
that you can build
uh there was like forums online
everybody's hanging out on Twitter
people are traveling all around the
world to go to all these conferences
together and I was like oh this is this
is just so cool right it's so inspiring
as as an engineer um uh uh just like
just starting out kind of one's career
uh it just just felt like such a a
relevant movement to to to to me and the
stuff that I found interesting and and
and I just just was just through the
moon excited about it and and and just
wanted to be part of it in any way I
could and and and so I just you know
quit my job I had no plans I had I had
no uh other job lined up and I was just
you know poking around online uh
probably being annoying to people uh in
various code reposts on GitHub um uh uh
uh just trying to figure out how do I
you know contribute and and get involved
and and that was really the starting
point I suppose wow so you quit your JW
first before anything yeah that's right
that's right wow that's very from all
the stories I've heard because people
usually have like a backup plan and then
they start this new thing yeah I had I
had I saved up enough so I remember
pretty distinctly i' saved up enough
money uh after school to to like live
for about a year basically without a job
and I was like okay great I'm lived on
on Ramen and and and and microwaveable
noodles or whatever um and in my like
little kind of apartment in San
Francisco and uh uh uh just yeah wanted
to just you know get into crypto somehow
I knew I'd get a job somehow and I would
make money if I needed to but um yeah I
I had no concrete plan other than
wanting to work on on ethereum and was
your first thing anchor or was that way
later oh that that was way later so my
first thing was actually I got a call
ironically uh from of all people the
folks at Alam research so this is before
FTX um this was like January 2018 um and
they told me about Alam they you know
they told me about the trading firm they
were building or whatever um I had no
intention on working at a trading firm
uh and uh uh uh uh and I was like all
right I'll give it a shot you guys seem
smart or whatever um uh uh uh uh this
seems interesting um I knew some of I
knew I knew one person there that was
like pretty pretty uh pretty brilliant
and so uh uh uh you know went there and
U it just wasn't for me I I didn't want
want to work in a training firm I I left
my job so that I can work on like smart
contracts and open source software and
decentralized you know uh uh uh uh uh
ledgers right um and so I was only there
for like three we three months and then
uh uh immediately jumped into working on
ethereum state channels which was one of
the kind of very invogue scaling
Technologies at the time um very much
the whole kind of ethereum world was
trying to wrap its head around how do
you make this thing scale It's a
Wonderful technology it's too slow for
any real use cases let's you know build
the kind of the scaling Technologies to
push the technology forward and so that
was the first thing that I got really uh
interested in and that was my my first I
guess real job in crypto um uh uh uh I
suppose after
Alam and then anchor was way later but
that was probably one of the most
important thing that happened to salana
because it is a what is it security
protocol for a lot of salana projects
really yeah yeah so what happened so I I
worked on a bunch of stuff in crypto for
the next couple years and then when the
Alam folks and the FTX folks started
getting involved in salana they invested
in salana they built serum they you know
started doing all that stuff they
basically called me up again and they're
like hey you know I know you don't want
to you know work on the trading firm I
know you don't want to work on the
exchange but we're doing the salana
thing now why don't you check it out and
I was like oh okay that's that sounds
interesting I I'll go check it out and I
learned a bit about salana and I it
seemed pretty incredible and and
inspiring and uh it was exactly kind of
what I was looking for uh in terms of
the type of blockchain I wanted to work
on that was scaling and and solving a
lot of these hard technical challenges
and so I came into salana and
immediately started building stuff and
you didn't have to get very far to
immediately run into the developer
experience being an issue where it was
very cumbersome to write smart contracts
on the network there was nothing really
analogous to like solidity or any of the
robust developer tooling that existed on
ethereum and it was really hard to write
secure smart contracts I very much
remember the very first hackathon on
salana where the large majority of those
projects were easily exploitable it was
super easy to hack and that was you know
mainly a function of of knowledge the
programming model was so different the
technology was so different nobody
really kind of uh uh fully wrapped their
head around what it meant to build smart
contracts on salana but then the other
part was just the tooling and I you know
basically came to the conclusion that
well nobody's going to use this thing
unless the developer tooling uh uh uh uh
improved um and that was like somewhat
true um there was definitely a lot of
folks that came in and then immediately
left because the tooling was so bad and
so I wanted to build stuff on the
network so I just decided to build
tooling for myself so that I can build
more stuff for myself and that was
ultimately uh the motivating factor and
so yeah built built anchor and yeah
definitely a large portion of the
compute now runs uh uh through smart
contracts that are that are using the
framework
you started with ethereum now with
Solano do you have a preference I mean
that that's a great question I mean
they're both so kind of different and
unique in so many different ways I mean
like a special place for me just given
I've spent so much time from like the
very very early days and having the
privilege of seeing it Grow from from
like from nothing really into what it is
today um and ethereum is uh also a
special place in my heart cuz it's
really the thing that inspired me to
come into crypto in the first place um
and and so uh yeah they're both pretty
incredible but I am uh very much uh uh
very actively involved in in salana
these days you have worked with ethereum
and salana so I think you're the perfect
person to answer the next question um
recently because of the price action you
know there a lot of debate over salana
versus eth and ethereum supporter would
say salana is this big Casino ethereum
could be more of a fundamental what's
your thought on this there's plenty of
speculation that's happened on ethereum
probably much more speculation and much
more casino gambling that's happened on
ethereum than any other network um so I
think that's a kind of a silly comment
that expresses nothing other than the
desire to want to stand on moral High
Ground rather than to discuss anything
substantive I think
if you want to talk about what's
happening on salana it's trading that
that's what's happening on salana I
think what a lot of people are coming to
the conclusion of is that one of the
main use cases is onchain decentralized
trading and currently the state of the
assets that are being traded on are are
are meme coins right um uh and this is
like the vehicle through which people
are using the technology which is
ultimately like these decentral trading
engines of sorts and I think it was
Chris Dixon that said it most uh
elegantly where you know he had this
famous oneliner where he says the next
big thing starts looking out like a toy
well meme coins are simply just a toy
the whole kind of idea of bringing
Capital markets on chain you know NASDAQ
at the speed of light as as Anatolia
would say is such a inspiring and and
Noble goal to genuinely improve the
state of of of of of global Capital
markets and so you know today is you
know the set of use cases on salana or
any other chain for that matter
predominantly speculative yeah
absolutely yes but you can say the exact
same thing for us Capital markets in uh
uh the early uh uh 20th century or the
late 19th century is the exact same kind
of growing pains and lessons and and and
it all comes down to kind of the world
kind of learning kind of this new kind
of Market structure learning this new
kind of you know uh
technological uh uh uh uh uh kind of
innovation that's happening that's you
know taking over the world so I would
assume you're um meme fan I mean it's
Nuance right I wouldn't say I'm neither
a meme fan nor uh a meme hater um I
think meme
coins EX Express you know a a a
sentiment in the market um that is the
result of of you know the past you know
several years of of good and bad things
that have happened in the industry right
um it's expressing the frustration with
all of the you know vaporware and and
and the rug pools and and and and you
know the the the unfairness uh uh uh in
the market Market um it's expressing
frustration with the regulatory
uncertainty and it's kind of like giving
the ultimate uh you know uh not to be
too crude but like you know middle
finger to to the world where it's like
you know you did this to us right
everybody's so frustrated we can't do
anything anybody that tried to actually
build something genuine uh uh uh you
know all the utility tokens for the past
four years or whatever have been met
with you know enforcement and Regulatory
action right anybody that was trying to
actually be on the bleeding edge of of
this stuff and and build something
useful for the world and so mcoins kind
of came out of this environment and then
you compare you you pair this with the
fact
that you know these decentralized
trading engines um now are kind of uh
such
a just like novel use case it's all kind
of this perfect storm that leads to the
meme coin frenzy that we have you have
to know what you're getting yourself
into with mem coins you know it's it's
it's speculative frenzy it's by no means
like the end state of the industry I
definitely wouldn't recommend anybody
putting their life savings into it and
you know treat it as an as a as a as a
you know an expenditure or whatever
right it would same way you would you
know play roulette or whatever at a
casino but um uh yeah mean coins are are
a sign of the times and an expression of
the collective sentiment of of of of
folks in the industry at the
moment so last cycle we had nft and game
fight and all all that right and that
brought a lot of new people new retails
into the industry and this time people
are saying mcoin is the new nft do you
think that is
right I think it's there's it's
partially true so I think what was
special about nfts is that it's it's
just artwork and everybody very
intuitively understands artwork and so
you can reach such a large audience that
isn't just a bunch of crypto nerds that
care about computers or whatever and and
and building open source software you
can start you know having nfts expressed
in mainstream culture in various
different ways right whether it's like
Eminem and Snoop Dog you know uh uh uh
you know wrapping or whatever they with
their board Apes uh uh or it's you know
clothing brands or whatever bringing you
know uh uh like Zara bringing okay Bears
into their their clothing stores or
whatever and so I think nft
are just like the form factor is so is
the most mainstream like form factor
thus far and I think the other thing
about nfts is that they're
fundamentally useful and that might
sound strange uh but like what nfts are
is they are really the perfect
technology to operationalize like a
luxury good to to operationalize status
signaling so other examples of this that
exists in the world right a Rolex why do
people buy a Rolex maybe there's some
like watch nerds that like the
engineering that goes behind it and the
craftsmanship and that's very genuine
and real but really it's a status
signaling thing it's like you're you you
you care about watch culture right it's
like why does somebody buy a Birkin bag
like why are handbags such a thing right
it's like the value of a Birkin bag goes
up over time it's like it's like it's an
investment for many people but it's the
same thing right it's like uh it's like
air Ma has this this you know amazing
brand or whatever but turns out a Rolex
isn't that great of a luxury good a
birken bag isn't that great of a luxury
good why uh because well you could only
see my Rolex if you're like in the room
with me right if I was wearing a Rolex
right now you wouldn't even see it right
I would have to like pull my sleeve up
and like put my my you know turn my hand
around be like oh yeah look at my Rox
and like you know it oh by the way it's
real too like you you don't just take my
word for it I need to like prove to you
it's real it's like how do you know it's
real it's like I don't know it's like
you know you just take my word for it or
whatever
but an
nft is much more effective and what an
nft allows you to do is it allows you to
flex that Rolex 24 hours a day 365 days
out of the year and you can prove it's
real uh online and you can signal kind
of in group or or tribal status um with
people not just kind of in in one
country not just at your restaurant not
just you know at the the valet where
you're showing off your Lamborghini or
whatever you could show off to anybody
all around the world and build you know
these subcultures around the
artwork and that is something that is
fundamentally like human right
storytelling and brand building and
artwork and you know ingroup outgroup
like tribal signaling is is is
fundamentally like useful and you could
just point to the entire billion- dollar
industry of of of of all luxury goods to
prove that point and
and so that to me is is nfts and so when
you ask the
question well are meme coins like the
next form factor it's like well meme
coins in some sense are they're the next
speculative frenzy they're the next hot
thing where a lot of money is going into
and there's a bunch of trading that goes
into it and so on and so forth but it's
not exactly the same I I think I think
it doesn't
capture the soul and and and the
affinity that artwork brings to people
um uh I think seeing a trading view of
chart is a very different thing and and
and and something that makes Rolex and
designer bags really valuable is that
the value keeps on going up right so
people see it as something that is
expensive and this whole concept of it
being expensive is constant right but
for nft it it's sometimes it's up
sometimes it's down people are not sure
is it is it expensive now what is it you
know where is it at now so how does that
replace luxury goods oh I don't know
about you but the price of a madlad is
quite expensive to
me um uh uh I think the price of a mad
it's what is it right now it's like let
me let me get you an actual number it's
it's 50 53 soul and in dollar terms what
is that that's like it's almost 10 grand
yeah 10 $10,000 um and if you look at
the chart over a long time it does keep
going up so so it does have that
property that that you've described um
that's not true for all nfts um and what
you're describing is simply the
abundance of nfts in the same way that
there's an abundance of clothing
companies to be clear there are many
failed clothing companies um I come from
Southern California like the home of of
of of of of clothing companies and many
fashion brands that that have been built
up that have been built um in like
Orange County and la and and and just
because there's a lot of failed clothing
companies it doesn't mean there's uh you
you know that Gucci doesn't exist um or
that air maze doesn't exist or or or or
that Nike doesn't exist or whatever and
uh not that Nike is like a luxury good
it's kind of a separate class of thing
but I digress uh uh and so yeah I would
say yes there are plenty of of nfts with
down only charts and that aren't worth
anything but there's also the Crypt
punks of the world and and those I think
will continue to get more and more
valuable as crypto becomes more and more
relevant to mainstream culture as we
spend more and more time online and as
having that profile pick viewed by
everybody around the world that is
learning what that actually means like
that'll just become more and more
valuable I think as time goes on as it
becomes more and more like part of the
world that we live in everything of
value is a meme but not all memes have
value I think that's the difference um
you know explain that let's let's take a
meme let's take Tesla
okay um why is Tesla valuable okay like
fundamentally Tesla is valuable because
Elon solves a lot of really important
problems for the world um uh uh you know
a lot of incredible engineering work
goes into that company but if you look
at the stock price you know uh it's
maybe a little different now but for
quite a long time it was trading like a
meme stock and it's like why is it
trading like a meme stock well it's
because people just believe in Elon
right people he allows people to dream
so big that it doesn't actually matter
what the value of of of of of Tesla is
today like we all collectively agree
that the value of Tesla tomorrow would
be more and probably beyond our wildest
imaginations because the guy can just
dream bigger than anybody else and the
story is just as important as what
actually exists today um it's because
it's the story that inspires people to
go work there it's the story that
inspires investors to invest in him it's
the story that inspires him to get
everybody in the world to believe that
he's going to do what he says he's going
to do and it's that
storytelling that is just as important
as anything else I think like you know
not to get like too like hung up on Tech
billionaires or whatever but like Steve
Jobs is the other person I think I think
was he the person somebody is like you
know the most powerful in the person in
the world is like the person who tells
the story or whatever right and memes
are just stories they're stories and
Collective beliefs and Collective
experiences that we all rally behind to
orient ourselves and to view the world
through a certain lens and that
influences our actions in in in in so
many important ways uh uh uh and the
things that we find valuable are are
influenced by these stories that we tell
ourselves and some things are more or
less objective like you know cancer
research is like more or less
subjectively valuable but then some
things are are are are much more
subjective it's like why is the Rolex
valuable that's a sub Ive meme right why
why why is the Lamborghini valuable it's
just a meme uh it's like okay there's
cool engineering work it goes fast or
whatever most of us don't actually care
about the cars some people certainly do
uh uh uh but what we actually care about
is the collective belief and social
proof around what it means to own the
car uh and and that's the meme and and
and and you know I think I think a
common theme with like the way I view
things is like as the world changes as
the way we live our lives change as our
out used change as our Behavior changes
then a lot of these fundamental
Primitives of our world will also change
and and I think the foundational concept
of of of status and and signaling
doesn't change but the form factor does
and that will change as the world
changes and and so that's kind of how
how I view it so let's say um one of
your neighbor this older Asian lady ask
you what you're doing what do you do for
a living and and you said I'm building
backpack wallet backpack exchange and
mads nft and this lady's like what are
those how do you explain to her I think
if I were to explain it to that profile
of a
person I would probably frame it in one
of two ways the easiest way would be to
compare it against like the stock market
um uh uh uh and and to it's not exactly
the same obviously
but uh uh the price mechanism is really
like the powerful most potent thing that
you know uh that runs all of crypto uh
uh uh uh and and and and that is like
the technology that matters most and
that that is what ultimately allows
everybody all around the world to
coordinate together um uh and you have
all these Collective people whether it's
folks here in Tokyo
or folks in Taiwan or folks in the US or
folks in in Dubai or in uh uh the UK or
Italy or wherever you know we all can
coordinate as a collective group around
a price um uh and capitalism kind of
just works because of that right uh and
and and so if I was to kind of maybe
explain it to that you know uh uh
somebody next door or whatever uh that
wasn't into crypto I think I would frame
it in terms of of
reimagining you know uh the way that
that markets and and and and maybe
stocks as the most concrete example run
or maybe not run the world but but you
know their its role in the world and and
generalizing that concept to uh uh uh to
things Beyond just equities um uh uh and
I think the next kind of most powerful
example and most most intuitively
understandable example is just nfts uh
even though might be the example that's
like not super invogue at the time um I
think the other example that I would
give is is the local kind of payments
here in Japan so Japan's a pretty
interesting place because it kind of
achieves a lot of what crypto wants to
achieve but but just in Japan itself um
I think a lot of kind of uh places in
Asia kind of achieve this but I don't
know if youve ever used used like pasmo
for example um uh it's like it's a
really wonderful user experience I open
up my my Apple wallet I have my credit
card in there I just you know deposit
some money into my pasmo and I can use
the subway I can I can buy lunch I could
buy dinner um and it all kind of just
works and the user experience is just
like Apple pay uh but the problem with
pmo and the problem with these payment
networks more broadly is that they only
work locally okay um and so if I go to
the US and I want to take a bus ride in
the US well pass mode doesn't work it's
like okay that's kind of sucks right uh
uh and so how do
you extend kind of uh uh you know uh uh
pain you know the this type of financial
technology whether it's payments um or
you know I use the the stock market as
another example but how do you how do
you generalize this
to like the entire world uh and I think
that is the other really special thing
about crypto is that it's borderless and
we're really building Financial
infrastructure uh uh and financial
technology for for not just one country
or one region but for the entire world
and I think that's like you know one of
the most magnificent parts of the
industry what you just said is pretty
inspiring because people are who are not
in crypto they always say hey let's say
Japan can achieve that then we can
probably scale that globally why do we
even need crypto but that mentality is
US versus them type of thing but it
should not be it should be like view as
one no no I mean I wholeheartedly agree
I think one of
the to be frank a little frustrating
things about the industry is folks tend
to get so caught up in their own like
myopic view of the world where it's like
only crypto right um but there's this
whole other world that exists and all
the important things are actually in
that other world it's not actually in
crypto it's in you know the goods and
services that you know run our lives or
whatever and so the way I like to think
about you know building stuff in crypto
is ultimately how do we bring all of
that value into crypto and just you know
uh bring that stuff whether it's on
chain or in crypto apps or whatever um
and and and and I think that's like a
really
important you know way to to solve
problems in the industry okay so you
built backpack exchange why an exchange
we already have a lot of exchanges out
there um is it because it's one of the
greatest business model or is is there
something you want to do with backpack
yeah so I mean it's a great question
because at the surface level you might
ask the question okay well there seems
to be a lot of exchanges why do we
another one all right um uh so let Let
Me Maybe lay some context for what's
happening right now in in The Exchange
Land and then to maybe share the unique
position exchanges find themselves in
and I think this will all collectively
add up to kind of this more broad story
that we all collectively agree which is
crypto is all about upgrading Finance
it's all
about you know to put it in the coinbase
terms uh uh replacing you know upgrading
the financial system and and hot
swapping the the back end of the
financial infrastructure that uh uh uh
uh runs the world but it's like that's
such a lofty goal it's like what does
that actually mean like like how do you
actually operationalize this and and and
and and and improve on Modern Finance
now let's like bring it back down into
reality so what's happening right now in
centralized Exchange Land so I think
here in Tokyo is a really good example
so literally last week or this week I'm
losing track of time I apologize some of
the world's largest exchanges got kicked
out of the app stores here there's no
mobile app now in Japan there's no
mobile app it you might as well not
exist mobile mo mobile app's the most
important thing right you can't be
offering
you know uh uh centralized Financial
Services in Japan uh without complying
with thew the laws and the rules and
regulations that exist in Japan um uh uh
and and that's just kind of like a a
base reality or whatever um but you can
see this happening in every large
economy in the world um um in the US
most of those companies don't kind of
dare operate because everybody's afraid
of the US government or whatever you
definitely don't want to break us laws
um in Europe
it it's like maybe another kind of
really great example uh in Europe every
single large crypto derivatives Exchange
in the world has been like shut down or
is really has has left the European
Union so everybody is has removed their
derivatives product it's like well okay
why it's because you know derivatives
are the most important product in crypto
for the for these companies right uh
it's where they make all their money
it's like why are you this is a huge
Market why are you doing this and The
Regulators are are are are cracking down
and folks that are not following the
rules are are are are are you know
getting in trouble right um and it's not
like you know sexy to say that or
whatever but that's you know if you want
to look at what's happening this is
what's happening right we can't pretend
like this isn't happening really
interesting about this is that these I
would say are like some of the best
products in crypto you know building an
exchange it's it's building a financial
institution uh it's it's it's it's a
very different process and set of skills
and a set of set of requirements than
that just building a normal technology
company this is kind of what's happening
right now uh in the exchange world and
there's not that many exchanges that
currently exist that have set themselves
up to operate in this world where the
industry is maturing it's getting to the
next level it's about to enter into kind
of you know the mainstream like uh uh
Financial kind of world that like you
know uh uh that really is where all the
value is right you see like the black
rocks of the world you know the stripes
of the world uh uh uh uh uh you know
really getting into the space and and
and really kind of going all in and
there's like a pretty kind of incredible
opportunity for a new exchange to come
along and to set themselves up for a
success in this more mature uh uh uh uh
uh industry now um uh and so that's
ultimately I think what what we're
trying to do where you know uh you know
I'm an American I come from the US uh uh
there's no kind of Market that you know
I I care about more than than my
homeland or whatever and and I want to
bring kind of crypto to kind of all of
us Capital markets kind of kind of uh uh
uh and to bring that globally as well
and so I think you know we are really
trying to bring that attitude and that
wonderful product experience not just to
the US but all around the world and I
think that's like one of the really
important reasons why we moved out here
to Tokyo it's because you know Asia
matters a ton you know whether it's
Tokyo or Taiwan or or Vietnam or or or
you know you know you know pick your
your favorite country out here um uh but
it's not just Asia either it's also
Europe and and and and and and it's also
the Middle East and uh uh crypto is this
really as I said earlier incredible
industry where it's borderless and to
build an exchange that can truly like
you know address the entire Market uh
allows you to build just like an
incredible kind of product where you can
actually start talking about this story
of upgrading the financial system um uh
and so that's kind of where we're coming
at it from and then you know once you're
there you can kind of segue into a lot
of specific stuff there's plenty of
stuff to talk about on the product side
whether it's the exchange or whether
it's the wallet um or whether it's
blockchains like salana foundationally I
think that's how we're oriented which is
very different than I think how
basically every other International
Exchange is oriented can I put it in a
simple way and say you started this
exchange following regulation from day
one is this like the more simple way of
saying yeah I think that's that's a
that's a that's a fair
characterization yeah okay and you just
said you live in Japan but Japan is very
famous for being very strict on crypto I
want to know you why you choose Japan
and what is one thing about crypto and
Japan that people outside of Japan might
not know so I think what people forget
is that Japan was a really important
center of gravity for crypto um uh uh uh
way back in the day like binance was
started in Tokyo um uh you know that you
know there's you know the the famous
Mount gaau days or whatever and then
there was the hacks that happened and um
regulation clamped down and and folks
left Japan as a result but I think the
thing that you know really brought us
back here is like that foundational like
like uh just like gravity that exists in
Japan with crypto with the fact that we
ultimately were anticipating a lot of
Tailwinds that would bring crypto back
to Japan and I think most recently with
you know I think there's some articles
floating around Twitter that you know
tax for crypto would go from like 55%
down to 20% or whatever you're starting
to see this now larger companies here in
Japan start putting you know Bitcoin on
their balance sheet um you're seeing
kind of more traditional institutions
like SBI trying to like really push for
things like you know Ripple to be
accepted in Banks um it's quite a
progressive uh uh attitude uh uh towards
the industry even before Trump was
elected and so we're talking about one
of the largest countries in the world uh
by GDP uh uh and so yes there is very
high high standards and rigorous rules
uh uh uh for compliance in the same way
that there's rigorous and high standards
in the US uh but it doesn't mean you
ignore the us and it doesn't mean you
ignore Japan it means you do all the
hard work so that you can build amazing
product in the country and so I think
that's kind of you know uh uh you know
some of the reasons why we found it to
be
exciting so is it fair to say it it has
tight regulation or is it just a
perception that people have on Japan oh
it's super tight no it's it's it's
definitely true we'll be the the first
exchange to have gotten the full license
from scratch since FTX collapsed um the
last one to have done it was was binance
it's a multi-year process it's not a
it's not something that you just like
fill out a form and then you get a
license and it's like yeah you can you
know serve crypto or whatever I'm really
curious so as a retail user or retail
Trader I look at for example Bitcoin
dominance chart to see where we are in
the market cycle and as an exchange
founder there are definitely other
metrics that you know about that I can't
see so what are different metrics you
look at to decide where we are in the
cycle and if there are some of the
metrics can you share with us and your
thoughts on where we are I mean there's
all of the typical Financial metrics
that you'll look at I think the more
subtle things to look for that you don't
need to be an exchange founder to look
at um is to Simply
look
at the number and the quality of
projects that are launching in the space
um and that is the single most important
thing you can basically forget about
looking at any type of financial metric
and you can simply look at human capital
uh just like look at the people that are
coming into the space and that will tell
you everything that you need to know um
and it here's like a simple example of
this when I came into salana in 2020 you
look around and you see who's coming
into salana
and a and based on this alone you could
immediately tell that salana would be
successful um and so who are some of the
people that came into salana you would
see folks um leaving their jobs from
Citadel to come into salana you would
see folks like jump trading coming into
salana obviously FTX and Alam at the
time uh you would see folks you know uh
uh leaving their jobs at like big tech
companies that were starting companies
whether it's apple or Facebook or or you
name it right um uh and that is the
single most important thing to look at
when investigating any type of of of of
crypto ecosystem uh whether it's an L1
or any other project for that matter uh
uh because ultimately it's just humans
building stuff and solving problems at
the end of the day um uh and so I think
that is ultimately the one thing that
matters especially now because as the
industry matures we're we're entering
like a totally different Market Dynamic
right it's no longer this I mean this is
well known at this point but it's no
longer this like separate kind of
idiosyncratic like market like the macro
affects crypto more now than it ever has
before and so you know you can talk
about things like you know a Bitcoin ETF
or a soul ETF or whatever and it's like
sure that will have some effect on the
price but interest rates will probably
have a much larger effect and you know
the larger macroeconomic policy that
affects traditional markets now also
affects crypto markets as more
established players larger funds in more
traditional institutions now allocate to
you know crypto as an asset class in a
way that wasn't kind of done before so I
think that is kind of how I would I
would view the market now people coming
into crypto right now how do you even
know who's coming into crypto and
building really amazing projects because
as a retail user everything sounds
pretty cool cuz you know everything is
Market it very well like this is Alpha
right this is where the money is made is
in figuring out how to do this and I
think what makes it pretty challenging
is it's really hard to tell the
difference between like somebody that's
actually building something great and
somebody who's just like a great
marketer or whatever there's a lot of
like levels of complexity that you can
go down it is very hard I think for most
folks they should not be in that game I
think for most folks there's maybe three
ways I would handle it the first way is
the simplest way which okay not
Financial advice most people should just
simply do a simple kind of barbell
strategy right if you're going to
allocate to crypto allocate some percent
of your portfolio 5% 10% pick your
number some something reasonable and
responsible that you're okay relatively
okay losing the majority throw it in
throw it into Bitcoin right bitcoin's
not going anywhere Bitcoin is like the
single most important asset in the world
uh uh you you'll be fine with Bitcoin
then there's some other asset then you
can start getting more speculative but I
think the one thing you can do that is
pretty unique in crypto is that you can
use the products and you can use the
products and see what's a great product
what are my friends using what are other
people using what actually brings me
value to my life that is one of the most
like spectacular things about
cryptocurrencies is that the users can
actually have ownership in the things
that they're using and bringing so much
value to the most famous example of this
is Uber right where I I don't know
exactly how true this is but it's my
understanding that Uber actually wanted
to issue stock to the drivers right you
run into Securities laws you know
they're not accredited investors or
whatever and so you can't actually get
the equity to to the folks that are
contributing in the network but in
crypto I can just spin up a Bitcoin
miner or a salon of validator and I can
start mining Soul or I can start
providing liquidity to I don't know pick
your favorite uh uh amm and I can start
earning you know Unis swap tokens or
whatever I can legitimately take part in
the operations of a decentralized
network and earn the asset okay uh uh
and so this is maybe maybe the other
really magnificent form of like really
investing your time uh and resources
where um you know just use what makes
sense to you and what what what you what
you enjoy um and I think that is a
spectacular way to find Alpha and to
make a lot of money honestly uh because
there's a ton of admittedly hard to find
but but great projects to choose from um
so I think that's maybe the other way
it's not just you know putting all your
eggs in one basket in crypto whether
you're a developer or like an investors
you are always going to see really shiny
objects everywhere popping out every day
how do you decide which narrative or
like which new Hot thing is a winner or
is it just another narrative that's
going to die out tomorrow yeah so it
depends on what you're doing right so if
you're just playing the momentum game
then then sure I tend to not play that
game the way I think about it is really
simply you think about it from first
principles what is fun fundamentally
valuable for the world what is
fundamentally going to improve people's
lives genuinely create something new
that's going to exist not for one cycle
not for two cycles but for as many
cycles as I can live through and to
focus on just the genuine Builders as as
trit as that might sound um that are
actually pushing the limits to sincerely
kind of change the world right there's
not that many of those the same way
there's you know not that many kind of
of those and and you know traditional
startups either I would generally
caution people away from playing that
momentum game and following metas and to
really just think about what is
fundamentally valuable and I think one
of the big mistakes that folks in
crypto kind of fall into to be honest
is coming to this Collective delusion
that value is not real that like
intrinsic value does not exist right
this this is the collective delusion too
many people in crypto believe they just
think intrinsic value isn't a thing it
turns out there are things that people
find valuable in the world like curing
cancer is valuable
instantaneous pay Global borderless
Payments is fundamentally valuable uh an
un
manipulatable fair market for trading is
fundamentally valuable for the world and
so these things do exist you just need
to find them and focus on those things
there's plenty of other things you know
there's speculative assets there's meme
coins there's gambling and all this
stuff and that stuff's all fun and fine
and has its place in the world but uh
for for for most people that are
thinking of it through the lens of like
investment I recommend you just keep it
simple and to focus on the things that
you know uh can push us all forward I
suppose I think most people struggle
with seeing your friends making a lot of
money with one meme coin and you're
still here investing in like those
stable assets you know you're up 20% but
that person's up 2,000% Charlie Munger
says if you're going to pick any of the
Dead deadly sins don't pick Envy there's
so many there's so many better sins than
Envy don't don't be envious of other
people right this is true in in crypto
but it's also true for everybody outside
of the crypto the quickest way to be
unhappy is to compare yourself to your
neighbor and that is a fast track to
misery so if you can sit down with
anybody tomorrow who would you want to
talk to and why I mean I said Charlie
Munger and and unfortunately he passed
away so that that he would have been a
pretty great choice doesn't prove of
crypto he doesn't which is why I would
love to talk to him I think he is
somebody that I think has so much to put
it in his own terms worldly wisdom he's
so much common sense and and so much
experience and and somebody whose ideas
uh just resonate a ton with me I'm a
pretty boring person I think in an
investment philosophy sense but um I
would love to talk with him about crypto
and and hopefully convince him that it's
not what do you call it it's not rat
poison and that there's lot of
interesting and genuine uh uh uh people
trying to make the world kind of uh uh
more interesting uh and hopefully better
off I think I struggle to convince a lot
of people from older generation as well
because as you said earlier the easiest
way is to compare the assets with
something like stock which is something
they're very familiar with but then they
can argue that hey with stock you have
all these assets the building the
factory and all that but with crypto
what do you have
how would you answer this question a
very great question the best example of
this is the world computer so I mean I
would just give an example of of salana
um or or ethereum or pick your favorite
smart contract platform where you have a
decentralized uh computer that's
operated by no one uh forgeable by no
one uh can be trusted and used by
anybody in any country regardless of
what religion uh they are regardless of
whether they're socialists or communist
or capitalists it can be China mainland
China it can be the US uh it can be
Korea it can be Europe it can be you
know it could be anywhere it doesn't
matter my view of the world we can all
collectively trust this shared Computing
machine and that is uh a really
incredible primitive to bring into the
world there are certainly plenty of
vaporware that exists in crypto in the
same way there's plenty of garbage that
exists if you you know flip through
penny stocks uh in the US uh there is
plenty of ridiculous companies uh
whether it's the dot bubble or any of
the worthless companies that IPO still
to till this day uh this is not unique
to crypto by any means but you can't
throw the baby out with a bath water and
you have to you know find the gems and
and and support those things and and and
uh you know everything's nuanced earlier
you talk about you know um knowing the
value of things that you built right
believe in there are things that's
fundamentally valuable but I'm sure with
so many ideas and so many different
things that you've done there has to be
something that you've given up on
something that you thought was so great
and then later on found out that it's
not working so I I guess the deeper
question would be how do you decide or
how do you tell the difference between
like a long-term play that just needs
more time or is it just not working for
example everyone's saying Jens San is
this genius but and then media um kept
on going for decades until AI took off
right so how do you decide you don't
have that many decades in your life to
prove yourself right or wrong there's
this almost lie that we're all told
right which is that you have this you
have these Geniuses that build these
incredible companies or whatever uh uh
that had this an incredible foresight to
to to see the future um and to build
something that brings us uh us into them
into the future whatever uh and I think
think that's somewhat true it's
certainly true for for some folks but I
feel like the journey is much
more mundane and much more like humble
than that you Ed an example of of Jensen
uh hang from Nvidia I think I saw a
video of him once where he was
describing something to this effect
where he said you know a lot of people
try to solve all these really hard
problems really quickly they're really
these like really sexy problems or
whatever I think he said something along
the lines of like you could just
focus on solving really small boring
problems but just for a really long
period of time and you can't foresee the
future necessarily like I highly doubt
he saw you know he probably knew AI
would be useful that gpus would be
useful and compute as a general resource
would be useful but to actually predict
that llms were going to take off in the
way that they did right that was like
almost impossible I suppose to predict I
suppose you can understand that
directionally AI is going to be a thing
and dire Ely you'll need more compute
and I think that was more or less
foreseeable once neural network started
really taking off I think the reality is
that people are kind of hill climbing
they show up to the office and they work
on a on a problem they do it every day
for a really long period of time and
sometimes it works out sometimes it
doesn't work out but uh you know to put
it in Charlie M mongers terms for the
people that do that over a sufficiently
long period of time it ends up working
out and it's impossible to predict it
you need to try to predict the future
you need to have foresight absolutely
you need to set yourself up for uh
success but you also need to set
yourself up for being lucky it's really
really hard to predict things and the
best thing that you can do is to like
Hill Climb and solve one problem every
day and to keep doing that until
hopefully something works out I love
that explanation because everyone thinks
you know starting a company or starting
a business is this really sexy and fun
thing to do right but it's actually a
lot little boring things adding up do
you have any plans for um backpack
globally in 2025 we are here in Japan uh
looking to go to market here so we're
going through the licensing process
that's going to be a big moment for us
that we're super thrilled and excited
about Europe is going to be the other
really big Market that we're just
absolutely thrilled about um we put an
enormous amount of work into it we're
still busting our butts trying to trying
to get that live uh ton tons of of of
folks involved with that and so we're
we're thrilled to to to go into Europe
uh and then I think really the biggest
moment for us is going to be all about
the seasons campaign we've put so much
work building the product building the
company you know getting license all
around the world just being able to get
to the starting line like it's it's
really like hard
to
overestimate or over kind of emphasize
how much work it is to just have the
opportunity to even go live um if you
want to do this in the way that we've
done it right if you want to do it in
both a responsible way and also in a
compliant way and so our real go to
market starts really in March uh and so
that's going to manifest itself in the
seasonal campaigns where we are finally
going to get the opportunity like to
bootstrap The Exchange now that you know
the core you know features are built and
find our genu genuine Community um and
so we're going to have you know the
campaign's probably going to run
anywhere from six months to a year and
uh yeah couldn't be more excited for it
for people that are new to your
exchange uh people who are actively
trading on other exchanges for example
binance and all that what differences
can they see immediately so whenever you
use an exchange you ask yourself one
question what can I do with my money
that's it so it's all about cost of
capital it's all about opportunity cost
of capital uh uh and if you can answer
that question and do it in a way such
that you can make people more money for
the exact same Capital uh or for the
exact same trade on your platform then I
think it's fair to say you will have a
reasonable business and so that's kind
of uh one one of the core kind of
questions ask and so let me give you an
example of something that you can do or
something that you will be able to do
once uh it's all said and done okay so
you deposit your soul into the
exchange and okay you lend it out into a
money market okay no problem other
exchanges have have lending in it you
start earning some yield okay maybe you
get 2% maybe you get 5% I don't know it
depends on what the demand for the
product is so okay great that you got a
nice yield product that's great but then
what if on top of the lending yield you
put St yield onto it so on top of that
you know 2 3 4 5% you get an additional
8% or 10% for staking the soul it's like
okay now you're stacking the yield
that's pretty interesting I haven't seen
anybody do that before but what if you
took it further what if you allowed that
lend to be used as collateral in a cross
margin cross collateralized system where
you can actually use that to trade
Futures it's like okay now that's quite
compelling uh now you're telling me that
I can get I don't know uh anywhere from
you know eight to uh uh uh 14 15% apy on
my
soul that's sitting inside of my margin
balance to trade Futures it's like oh
well that's kind of interesting that's
that's new so this is is kind of the
inspiration for our futures product
product so we we we call them not
Perpetual Futures we call them interest
bearing futures because we want to be
able to use kind of the the the capital
kind of um uh uh as kind of productively
as possible where uh you have spot spot
margin borrow lending Perpetual Futures
all C cross collateralized cross margin
together in a single sub account really
in a way that nobody has done since FTX
which you say a lot of terrible things
about FTX the product was great people L
the product um uh and I think we have
built something genuinely new unlike FTX
unlike any of the other existing
exchanges and really through this lens
of how do we kind of productively make
people money really maybe the starting
point for the conversation when it comes
to the product why aren't other
exchanges doing that the only answer I
can really think about is just path
dependency where these are huge
companies they're huge codebases they're
great businesses it's a very risky thing
to change and unless you're going to
rewrite this from scratch it's very hard
to it's a very hard change to make and
so I think there's just a practical
reason that it's just hard to change
these things um and maybe their users
are also just kind of used to the way
that it's built I think path dependency
is the main reason uh and you can ask
this question to any big company and any
startup that has built something new why
didn't Facebook build Tik Tok like I
don't know like they they had videos on
Facebook right it's like or why didn't
Instagram do it they could have done it
uh but they didn't yeah it's pretty hard
to change these things after the fact I
think a lot of us users listen to what
you just said and are going to be very
intrigued but the question will be where
does the Y come from an exchange or any
product in crypto should always be able
to answer these questions very simply
like exchanges are complicated but
they're not that complicated okay and if
somebody is not answering a question
simply it's something is wrong okay so I
I I think that's my general view of the
world so where does the yield come from
it's very simple so there's two sources
in the example that I shared with you
the first is a peer-to-peer money market
so if you've ever used like a or any
like dii protocol um it's very simple
you have this concept of like a lending
pool uh where you put assets into and
then you have borrowers that come and
pull assets out of the pool and then you
have a simple utilization curve uh which
defines your interest rate model and as
utilization goes up so as more of the
assets are borrowed then the interest
rate goes up and up and up and as the
utilization goes to 100% there is some
threshold that you know spikes up or
whatever uh uh but the you know the
maybe those technical details don't
matter the simple answer is it comes
from borrowers so so borrowers simply
pay the lenders the yield and it's
really as simple as that it's it's kind
of funny to say it's like where do yield
come from the people that are borrowing
it's borrow lending um so that's the
First Source the Second Source uh which
admittedly we haven't done yet I've been
testing the waters on Twitter and
testing the waters uh by asking our
users and and people are overwhelmingly
positive about it um uh which is staked
yield so uh uh there's all these assets
that are sitting on exchanges doing
nothing there's no marginal added risk
from staking your soul basically what I
want to do is to whenever you deposit
Soul into the platform just stake it
instantly um and if you lend you get you
get a tap into that yield uh uh so where
does that extra 8 10% come from it's
simple it just comes from staking in the
same way that you stake to any validator
you can do it in your wallet you can do
it manually if you want um but the
beauty of having a centralized exchange
is that if you just stake it on behalf
of the users then you can you you get
that extra Capital efficiency where you
not only get the margin collateral you
not only get the lending yield but you
also can get the staked soul apy and
that is something nobody has done before
um and it's something that really in
exchange is you uniquely suited to be
able to pull off and so I think that is
a uh I me to answer your question that's
where that's where the yield comes from
it's like lending uh borrow lending and
and and sake soul I think it's great
because a lot of people are interested
in this extra stake yield but they're
too scared to do it themselves on Defi
and a lot of new users I think would
really appreciate this um feature yeah I
knowly agree any advice for someone
who's experienced ing their first Bull
Run I think the main piece of advice I
would give is to not think about making
it in a single
cycle you're not going to make it in a
single cycle some people might some
people might get luggy in the same way
some people might win the
lottery but if you free yourself from
the single cycle
mentality then it liberates you to make
decisions with a multicycle mind
and I think when you're thinking at the
scale of multiple Cycles um you can make
much better decisions that will set
yourself up for I don't want to say
Surefire success but a much more likely
probability that you're successful and I
think I think that is is the main thing
um don't fomo into things don't be
envious of your friends that are getting
rich uh your time will come and and and
just you know do it over multiple Cycles
not
one I love that um okay one last
question
is if you can erase one crypto narrative
right now because it's garbage which one
would it be that's a that's a good
question that's gonna surely make me a
lot of
friends um Let Let Me Maybe touch on a
narrative that hits close to home to me
so I think there is
this
narrative that
decentralized exchanges and centralized
exchanges are like at odds with each
other and that decentralized exchanges
are here to replace centralized
exchanges that cannot be further from
the truth and it fundamentally
misunderstands the role that centralized
exchanges play in the market so let me
give you my favorite example of this so
Circle uh they don't call themselves a
centralized exchange but for all intents
and purposes circle is a centralized
exchange you could deposit uscc from any
chain uh so you deposit usdc from Soul
and then you can trade it for usdc on
eth or you can deposit Fiat and you can
trade Fiat for usdc on soul and they
solve all of these hard compliance
issues and do all of this work so that
they
can go to the treasury Department uh
give them Fiat and and get us treasuries
and bring all of that yield and funnel
it on chain right that that's kind of
the incredible thing that that that
Circle and these other stable coins have
done if you take a look at defi like on
salana for example it's all using usdc
and so you have a centralized exchange
literally fueling all of defi okay uh
this concept that centralized exchanges
and decentralized exchanges are odds
with each other is kind of silly to me
and the way I think about centralized
exchanges is it's not about
centralization versus decentralization
that is more or less a I don't want to
say meaningless but that is an
implementation detail that is a lot less
important
than reframing the conversation which is
it's not about centralization for
decentralization it's about compliance
versus censorship resistance and the
compli compliance is sensor it leans
into censorship by Design if you are
compliant it means you have to censor
users that are breaking the law like
that that's what compliance means uh uh
and so there there's different rules and
requirements for different places all
around the world depending on where
you're serving users but the reason why
you do that is because it allows you to
tap into all of the value in the real
world uh it's you know real world assets
or whatever whether it's it may be
treasure yield is like the simplest
example of this where yeah uh Circle has
the ability to unilaterally freeze any
usdc because if law enforcement tells
them to they need to be able to do it
and what they get in exchange for that
is the treasury yield and people care a
lot about getting that treasury yield
this is what you know you know it sounds
so silly to say to say to like anybody
outside of crypto but to people in
crypto this is like such a foreign
concept but this is was what centralized
exchanges are meant to be doing and this
is why the compliance piece is so
important it's because they are this
very important compliant actor in the
space that allows them to bring like all
of the goods and services and all the
value from the traditional economy and
to bring that
to like you know the crypto economy and
and what exchanges are ultimately doing
is they're bridging one economy into
another economy in back whether it's
Fiat whether it's stable coins uh
whether it's providing a compliant uh
order book for institutional actors that
have you know uh specific rules and
requirements around you know how custody
is done or whatever it's a separate role
that that they're playing in the space
uh and it's a super important one and so
I think this is like the main uh uh a
misunderstanding and so when I see folks
saying like oh I'm G to be like the
decentralized binance or whatever or
like we're going to kill coinbase or
whatever because like our onchain thing
is way better I'm like okay your onchain
thing is awesome this is what we need to
push for in the industry but don't throw
the py out with the bath water like a
lot of other companies are doing really
important work that you need to be able
to operate a fully onchain uh econ
and so I I think it's a very nuanced
conversation and I think that is like
one of the more important misconceptions
that hits close to home for me I love
your explanation because we talk about
this a lot okay so do you think this
argument between centralization and
decentralization in terms of exchanges
is one way for dexes to get more
customers because they spread this fear
in you that centralized exchanges will
collapse or might collapse one day and
it's out of your control yeah so a
couple things so firstly I don't think
it gets them many customers I I
genuinely don't I think I ultimately
product is all that matters and and
whatever you kind of say on Twitter
whatever is more or less meaningless and
people you know don't care so I I think
that comes from the desire to want to
differentiate oneself in the market and
to tell some story that justifies Your
Existence in the world or whatever but
ultimately does nothing the the second
thing is what you said is just factually
false people don't want to admit this
I've been telling everybody the story
recently cuz I've just been so shocked
when I when I when I read this I opened
up a wallet app the other day um and I
was setting up my C phas and uh it
wasn't backpack it was another wallet
and what they tell you in the app was
just just jaw-dropping what they tell
you is $4.2 billion is lost from people
who lose access to their seed phas every
year $4.2 billion this is more than
every exchange combined every year so
this whole meme that get your money off
of exchanges uh and into self- custody
is well-intentioned it might be the
right advice for like .01% of the
population that knows how computers work
and is an expert in cryptography and you
know is is like you know
super uh kind of uh Savvy with with with
self- custody but it does not work for
the large majority of the human race in
fact I would say it's net negative if
you force everybody to have self-
custody you have to look at what you're
doing right you're giving people a knife
and they're all stabbing themselves uh
you you have to admit that right one of
the things I'm most excited about is
solving that problem I think you
genuinely can have genuine self- custody
everything that really makes the
industry so important and so incredible
but without you know the dangers of
self- custody in its current form so you
know I I I I won't go into the technical
details of this but I think these
problems are solvable I genuinely think
that there will be you know iterations
of self- custody that quote unquote
normal people will be comfortable with
but I think to address the comment that
you made that Meme and that narrative
that is spread is mostly just you know
for lack of a better word it's frivolous
marketing with no like uh foundation in
reality right and it's not being
intellectually honest with what's
actually happening to people all around
the world but I think you hear that so
often then you start believing it right
because that's what everyone's telling
you after FTX they're like oh exchange
as big as FTX could collapse and take
all your money hey why don't you just
you know hold on to your own seed phrase
but I always have this I don't know like
this thought in my head I would never
ask my mom to hold her a seed phrase
because it's almost impossible right and
I would actually like to know how you
would solve that problem maybe just like
if you have time um maybe like a simple
explanation because it's really
interesting yeah
so it's it's hard to answer this
question without getting technical but
let let me I'll explain it a high level
the technical term people like to use is
account abstraction so the the concept
is really simple instead of your wallet
or let's say your Ledger owning like
your asset instead a smart contract owns
your asset and your Ledger simply
controls the smart contract um and and
with that small
change my view is that you can solve all
of these self- custody problems with
genuine self- custody you can solve all
of them and a simple example of of how
you might do this so uh I don't know if
you're familiar with like the way multi
sigs work like a squad multis sick on
salana or an nois safe on ethereum
basically it's a primitive that allows
you to basically control assets with you
know multiple different wallets that
have to collectively come together to
use the wallet so instead of me just
signing something on my ledger I need to
sign something and you know you Bonnie
need to sign something and maybe that's
enough it's like a two of three and and
and we can collectively use the assets
together so if you just put all of your
your assets into a multisig and then you
carefully
construct the signers of that
multisig you can do some magnificent
things so before going into the
technical details let me tell you the
user experience of a new product that
we've been iterating on in private so
this isn't released yet this is It's on
it's it's on Main it's on mainnet we
have a some users that are using it but
the user experience is as follows you
log into your exchange account email
password tofa no problem just like
logging in coinbase or binance or
whatever you can trade you click buttons
whatever you go look at your wallet you
have like your trading account but then
there's also this like other account
it's like a web three account thing it's
like what is that well you go in there
and you have your nfts in there that's
kind of cool well you can use defi you
can like maybe you know use a A kamino
or a that's kind of cool you can swap on
Unis swap or Jupiter well that's kind of
cool you can send any tokens that are
not even on the exchange well that's
kind of cool and whenever you use this
wallet it feels like you're just using
the centralized exchange maybe you click
to sell an nft and you see tofa okay I I
pull out my phone I open up my
authenticator app I type in my tofa no
problem I'm used to that right it's like
any other app on web too but then
there's an extra step which is is I as
I'm ask for a signature and it's it's my
ledger or my hot wallet or my pass key
or whatever private key you want to use
it doesn't matter I'm going to say
Ledger for this conversation so I do the
2fa but then it asked me for 3fa and my
ledger is just the
3fa and so I sign with my ledger and
then that's it I used my wallet no
problem and and and that is a very
familiar user experience I just have my
centralized exchange account I just have
this extra wallet thing that's a 3fa I
could use it a 2fa I don't need a 3fa if
I want 3fa is just kind of nice if you
want to be like super skure and it could
be a pass key it could be a ledger it
can be a hot wallet it can be something
that's stored in my iCloud account it
doesn't really matter you can have
various different forms of this but that
is a really nice user experience and but
it's self- custody it's like well what
are the catches here what happens if I
throw my ledger into the ocean and I
don't have a backup well it's like oh
well like how do I get how do I get my
money back how do I get my nfts back no
problem no problem Bonnie just call up
customer support just you know say Hey
you know I'm Bonnie uh maybe here's my
my my ID uh can you please give me my
wallet back uh uh uh you know that'd be
great no problem the same way you would
recover your exchange account and the
same way you would recover your bank
account you would recover your wallet
that is a great user experience but then
you might ask the
question well this sounds too good to be
true like what's the catch right like
like you must be selling me something
right you must be there must be some
gimmick here right what happens if an
FTX situation happens what happens if
the exchange goes under do I lose all my
assets and my answer is no you don't
lose the assets all you need is your
Ledger and all you need is an internet
connection to a validator and you get
your assets back no problem and that's
the user experience and then you know I
can I'm happy to talk about the
technical construction um it's it's a
bit there's some details in there I'm
I'm happy to go into but that's the user
experience and that solves all of the
recovery problems with people losing
their assets due to you know self-
custody as it exists today so if I can
call up customer support and ask for my
ACCESS back isn't that just in central
exchange ah it's subtle so the user
experience is the centralized exchange
but the custody is not and the reason
why it's not is because no matter who
you are no matter where you are in the
world you can always unilaterally get
your assets back even if the exchange
tries to steal from you so if backpack
if Armani is evil right Armani's a
terrible person he tries to steal
Bonnies he tries to steal Bonnies crypto
it doesn't matter Bonnie can always be
could always be like nope I I don't
think so I can never steal your your
assets okay so so let me let me tell you
why so it's a multisig under the hood so
the way it's constructed is as follows
it's a two of four multisig technically
it's two five but I'm going to say two
four just because it's easier to
understand less confusion so it's a two
four multis and there's two tiers of
signers the first tier is are their
instant signers okay so one of them is
your wallet so it's your Ledger and then
the other one is the exchange
infastructure
so by default you use the instant
signers you sign into your exchange
account your backpack exchange account
you click sell my nft or trans or stake
my soul and that'll give you one
signature where it'll just be the ex the
centralized exchange will sign no
problem okay so that gives you one
signature um the second signature is
your 3fa so that's your your Ledger or
whatever and so now you have two
signatures transaction sign sent to the
network boom you you have an instant
signer okay no problem so that's the
normal happy path of of just that nice
user experience where it looks and feels
like a centralized exchange so that
that's the first tier the second tier of
signers is you have two additional
signers which round out to the four
members of the multisig one is also your
Ledger however your Ledger now has a
time lock on it so for Simplicity let's
just say seven days okay so if you want
to use this signer it'll take seven days
to land this transaction onto the
network it will not be instant now uh uh
so you can always come together with
your instant signer say say backpack
goes Belly Up We're bankrupt or whatever
you FTX it no problem you Bonnie just
opens up her validator or goes to you
know some other website pulls out her
Ledger signs with the first one instant
and then signs with the second one which
it will happen in seven days in seven
days you'll get all of your assets back
no
problem now there's the fourth signer
the fourth signer is also the exchange
and the trick is really
simple instead of it being a 7-Day time
lock it just has to be
longer than your time
lock so let's make it simple let's say
it's like 90 days so the exchange is a
90day time lock it could be 14 days it
can be 30 days whatever you want let's
just say 90 days to be extreme so now
there is four signers here there's an
instant signer with which is your Ledger
there's an instant signer which is the
exchanges infrastructure which you just
have to be signed in to use it there's
an in there's a 7day signer which is
your exact same Ledger and then there is
a 90day signer which is the exchanges
infrastructure it's like an exchange
cold wallet of
sorts and so what happens then is if you
lose your wallet say your lger goes in
the ocean your you God forbid you pass
away or whatever and a loved one needs
to recover it no problem absolutely no
problem what'll happen is the exchange
will come it has two of the four signers
it'll do do one instantly and then the
the second one will just be on that
90-day time lock and that'll hit the
network and in 90 days you'll get your
money back no problem boom okay so
there's one more case that we have to
handle which is what happens when
backpack tries to steal from you that's
that that is super important to claim
that you have self- custody well the
trick is that you can always land your
transaction before the exchange so if
the exchange tries to steal from you it
takes the instant signer puts that onto
the network done and then it has the
90day signer it takes that puts onto the
network but now it's locked for 90 days
you have to wait 90 days so you just
need a single altruistic human on the
planet
Earth that's it just one one out of you
know however many billion people exists
on this planet to see that and then no
problem uh you pull out your Ledger you
sign it instantly and then you sign to
the 7-Day time lock and then you have
your funds back in 7 days while the
exchange takes 90 days and then you
always have your assets and there is a
single case that this does not cover and
the reason and in this case is kind of
fundamental uh and you it's basically
impossible to cover this if you want to
maintain self- custody if you don't care
about self- custody then then you can
cover this but if you want self- custody
you can't cover that you can't cover the
scenario so the scenario that is not
covered is the scenario where two things
happen first thing is you lose all
copies of your Ledger you have no seed
phrase no ledger so you lose it and then
also at the exact same time somebody
stole it from you and is trying to and
steals from you basically and is trying
to take all your money if that happens
both you have you don't have any backup
anywhere you have zero backups and
somebody is stealing from you they have
it they have your Ledger then for all
intents and purposes they are you right
they they own they they have the self-
custody now right nobody else in the
world has it and so if you want self-
custody you cannot solve that you cannot
solve that scenario but um but uh but
that's kind of the The Edge case but um
yeah I hope I've convinced you that that
it is genuine self- custody
now is it possible to call up customer
support and said this is the situation
I'm in and I'm actually Bonnie that
person is not oh great question so to
this is really
I mean it's going to this might this is
such a contentious point but this is
really where kyc shines because we kyc
everyone there's like a rigorous process
for account recovery it's like you can't
just randomly recover your bank account
right you can't just randomly recover
your centralized exchange account you
actually have to go through the
compliance team right you actually have
to show government documents and show
your face right um and so the
kyc ironically provides another level of
defense for exactly that situation and I
mean I don't know about you but for me
personally I don't want just some random
company going through that recovery
process right I want a a rigorous
financial institution that has a super
high bar for for doing this type of
thing that that is trained for this and
so I think that is really where where
the kyc and the compliance shines is for
exact is for that recovery procedure I
know that's contentious I know a lot of
people really hate the idea of of Ky
seeing their wallet or whatever but um
but when it comes to this and I think
for the majority of people just the
value ad outweighs uh the negative but
you can certainly take this construction
and apply in a non- kyc uh a scenario I
think you know you can have various
options for different types of people
and I think that's and I think that's
great thank you for the explanation it's
really really insightful thank you so
much it was a great interview yeah thank
you so much Bonnie I appreciate it